

Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: <a href="mailto:consultant@londonresearchinternational.com">consultant@londonresearchinternational.com</a> www.LondonResearchInternational.com

# Mrs. Kyei

**NATIONALITY**: American

## **SUMMARY**

Mrs. Kyei has more than 7 years of work experiences in Rule of Law, Development in Africa, Program Management, and International Relations. With highly diverse educational background, she has completed various intern/work experiences in different areas. With her travel abroad experience, she is familiar with sub-Saharan Africa, Europe, and Latin America.

#### **EDUCATION**

- University of Pennsylvania, (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania) /2012/ MA Environmental
  Management Studies (Certificate: Environmental Studies)
   Thesis Topic: "How Micro-financing can be used to advance environmental sustainability and
  women empowerment in Ghana." Presenter (Capstone Project in Africa), Masters of Liberal
- Les Aspin Centre for Government- Marquette University/ Dec 2010-Feb 2011/
   Liberia Exchange Program 2010-11
   U.S State Department Assisted Professional Exchange and Capacity Development Training on Leadership with Integrity in a Post-Conflict Governance Context of Liberia.
- Seton Hall University, (South Orange, New Jersey) /2007/ BA English, Political
   Science
- Oxford University Saint Hugh's College (Oxford, UK) / May 2005-August 2005/
   Study Abroad (Concentrated on History, Philosophy, English and Catholic Studies)

## **EMPLOYMENT RECORD**

Arts Forum 2012

- American Bar Association (ABA), World Justice Project (United States)
  - Independent Consultant (August 2012- present)
  - Research Consultant (March 2011-July 2011)
  - ➤ Rapporteur (June 2011) Business, Economic Development, and Rule of Law session World Justice Forum III (Barcelona, Spain)
  - ➤ Rule of Law Index Program Associate (April 2010 August 2010)



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: <a href="mailto:consultant@londonresearchinternational.com">consultant@londonresearchinternational.com</a> www.LondonResearchInternational.com

- Rule of Law Index Program Assistant (January 2008- March 2010)
- Justice Africa (Advocacy organisation and research institute, London, UK)
  - Research and Fundraising Intern (January 2013-May 2013)
- The Netter Centre for Partnership, University of Pennsylvania (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania)
  - Date Coordinator/Manager and Civic Missions/ Graduate Research Associate
     (September 2011-January 2012)
- The Wharton School of Business, University of Pennsylvania (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania)
  - Research Assistant (August 2010- December 2010)
- ProWorld (Cape Coast, Ghana)
  - Ghana Corp Intern (January March 2012)
  - > Internship placement: Christian Rural Aid Network (CRAN Microfinance)
- The Washington Centre for Internships and Academic Seminars (Washington, District of Columbia)
  - ➤ International Affairs Program (January 2007-May 2007)
- Jubilee USA (Advocacy strategies on international debts cancellation)
  - Research and Communication Intern (January 2007-May 2007)
- The Protection Project, John Hopkins University SAIS School (Advocacy for 'trafficking in persons' violation)
  - Research Intern (January 2007-May 2007)

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research/ management experiences;

- Responsible for development and implementation of Index methodology
- Administration and collection of surveys
- Assistance in the expansion of Index in sub-Saharan Africa
- Collection, evaluation and negotiations of costs of proposals
- Coordinated implementation of Rule of Law Program
- Social media management

Professional event attended;

World Justice Forum IV (The Hague, Netherlands) 2013; World Justice Forum III (Barcelona,
 Spain) 2011; World Justice Forum II (Vienna, Austria) 2009; American Bar Association-



Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Annual Meeting 2009 (Chicago, Illinois); University of South Carolina (Columbia, South Carolina) presentation on the Rule of Law Index.

Travelled to Liberia to develop a methodology for the pilot of lower income countries particularly for sub-Saharan Africa (November 2008). Coordinated meetings with rule of law experts, local government officials, and potential polling companies/partners to collect firsthand information regarding various survey data gathering capabilities and local mapping. Finally develop sampling techniques and plans for qualified respondents (November 2008).

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

- Certificate, Leadership with Integrity Training 2011
- Member, Liberia Professional Network (Liberia Diaspora Committee)
- Member, Young Professionals in Foreign Policy, Washington, District of Columbia
- Member, Young African Professionals, Washington, District of Columbia
- Member, Sigma Tau Delta, International English Honor Society, 2007
- Graduated with Departmental Honours (English), 2007; Servant Leadership Scholarship, Seton Hall University, 2004.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Bright, C. (with Botero, J, Martinez, J, Ponce, A and Pratt, C.), The rule of law around the world, in Agrast, et.al. (2010), The World Justice Project Rule of Law Index 2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012. Washington D.C: The World Justice Project

#### LANGUAGE

English